Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. 16mm microfilm Legal Department records, 1916-1958 and undated RL.11718
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. 16mm microfilm Legal Department records
1916-1958 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company
RL.11718
3.0 Linear Feet
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. It is headquartered in New York. Collection includes correspondence, invoices, claim forms, reports and other printed materials. Topics include billing, clearances, federal laws, insurance claims, taxes and unsolicited ideas. Companies and organizations represented include American Association of Advertising Agencies (AAAA), American Federation of Musicians (AFM), American Federation of Radio Actors (AFRA), Federal Communication Commmission (FCC), Federal Trade Commission (FTC), Atlantis Sales, Ballantine, Bowman Dairy, Elgin Watch, Ford, General Cigar, J.B. Williams, Johns-Manville, Kodak, Kraft, Lever Brothers, Owens-Illinois Glass, Pan Am, Pond's, Scott Paper, Seven-Up, Shell, Standard Brands, Swift, U.S. Brewers Foundation, U.S. Playing Card, W.F. Young, Ward Baking and Weco. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Organized into the following series: General Files; Accounts; Advertisers Liability Insurance; Edward G. (E.G.) Wilson papers
Biographical / Historical
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. It is headquartered in New York.
Beginning in the 1930s, documents from several JWT departments and functions were microfilmed, including Legal Department, Treasurer's Office, As Broadcast Scripts and Commercials for Radio and Television, Investigations, Publicity Department, Artwork, Consumer Panel, and Radio/Television Department. Documents were microfilmed in no order, and typed and hand-written indices were produced for the microfilms. It is believed that once microfilmed, most of the original documents were destroyed.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. 16mm microfilm Legal Department records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1987.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
J. Walter Thompson Company. 16mm microfilm Treasurer's Department records
J. Walter Thompson Company. Account files
J. Walter Thompson Company. Edward G. Wilson papers
J. Walter Thompson Company. Legal Department records
Advertising; Advertising -- History; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; Wilson, Edward G., 1909-1993
- General Files, 1930-1956 and undated; 1
  - AAAA (American Association of Advertising Agencies) Radio Directors Guild, 1945-1946 (Reel 900)
  - AAAA Committee on Radio Broadcasting, 1946-1947 (Reel 900)
  - AAAA general files, 1945-1947 (Reel 900)
  - AAAA Radio Writers Guild, 1945-1946 (Reel 900)
  - AAAA Special Committee on Radio and Television Policies, 1946-1947 (Reel 900)
  - ACRA (Association of Canadian Radio Artists?), 1945-1946 (Reel 900)
  - Advertising Council, 1946 (Reel 900)
  - Advertising--Attacks on use in commerce, 1942-1944 (Reel 430)
  - AFM (American Federation of Musicians) general files, 1943-1947 (Reel 996)
    Scope and Contents
    Vol. 1
  - AFM (American Federation of Musicians) general files, 1946 (Reel 900)
  - AFM--Network contracts, 1949-1953 (Reel 996)
  - AFM--Survey of contracts in event of AFM strike, 1948 (Reel 996)
  - AFM--Television, 1948-1953 (Reel 996)
  - AFRA (American Federation of Radio Artists) Letters of Adherence: NBC, CBS, ABC and Mutual, 1943-1947 (Reel 900)
  - AFRA general files, 1946-1947 (Reel 900)
  - AFRA--"Live" Code vol. 1-3, 1940-1952 (Reel 996)
  - AFRA--Code "transcriptions", 1939-1952 (Reel 996)
  - AFRA--Code of Fair Practice for Phonograph Recordings, 1953 (Reel 996)
  - AFRA--Negotiations, 1940-1950 (Reel 996)
  - AFRA--Total fee paid AFTRA performers, 1953 (Reel 996)
  - AFTRA pension and welfare fund, undated (Reel 1013)
  - Althea Revere files, 1954 (Reel 997)
  - American Guild of Musical Artists (AGMA), 1944-1947 (Reel 996)
  - American Guilde of Variety Artists (AGUA), 1944-1955 (Reel 996)
  - Arbitration, 1944-1953 (Reel 996)
  - Art vol. 1, 1940-1948 (Reel 996)
  - ASCAP, 1940 (Reel 375)
    See also reel 248
  - Billing by accounts, 1955-1956 (Reel 1009)
  - Bonuses, 1943-1956 (Reel 1009)
  - Budget, 1955-1956 (Reel 1009)
  - Burbridge and Geraghy--Release for "Up on Your Wings" song, 1940 (Reel 375)
  - California Use Tax, 1945-1950 (Reel 1012)
  - Chronological files, 1954 (Reel 1009)
  - Chronological files, 1956 (Reel 1009)
  - Contests, lotteries, etc., vol. 1-2, 1924-1953 (Reel 996)
  - Copyright, vol. 1-4, 1932-1953 (Reel 996)
  - Correspondence vol. 1, 1947-1953 (Reel 998)
  - Correspondence--Right of privacy, vol. 1-2, 1930-1953 (Reel 998)
  - Estimates, 1945-1952 (Reel 998)
  - Federal Communication Commission--Radio and television, 1934-1953 (Reel 998)
  - Federal Food, Drug and Cosmetic Act, vol. 1, 1938-1949 (Reel 998)
  - Federal Trade Commission, vol. 3-4, 1948-1954 (Reel 998)
  - Federal Trade Commission--Concept of "free", 1939-1949 (Reel 998)
  - Foreign--General, vol. 1, 1942-1953 (Reel 997)
  - Frequency Modulation (FM radio), 1948 (Reel 997)
  - Gullerno Toro v. Donald Johnston (Bogota Colombia), 1956 (Reel 1012)
  - Idea and release, 1944 (Reel 375)
    Bill Irving on Frank Sinatra and Bert Wheeler play tennis with Bill Tilden
  - Idea rejection letters A-Z, 1947 (Reel 315)
  - Idea releases A-Z, 1947 (Reel 315)
  - Ideas--Correspondence and rejections vol. 2, 1947-1954 (Reel 997)
  - Ideas--Releases and rejections, 1948-1951 (Reel 738)
  - Memoranda, 1944 (Reel 997)
  - Motion pictures vol. 1, 1942-1949 (Reel 997)
  - Motion pictures vol. 2, 1950-1953 (Reel 1012)
  - Music--Clearance, assignments, cases, etc., 1935-1954 (Reel 997)
  - Personnel--General and problems vol. 1, 1947-1952 (Reel 1009)
  - Personnel--JWT policies and procedures vol. 1, 1948-1949 (Reel 1009)
  - Radio Writers Guild, 1949-1954 (Reel 1009)
  - Radio Writers Guild, 1950-1953 (Reel 993)
    Vol. 6-10, 12; correspondence and chronological files
  - Radio Writers Guild, vol. 1 #6, 1949 (Reel 414)
  - Radio Writers Guild, vol. 1-5, 1947-1948 (Reel 375)
  - Radio--Facilities and general, 1941-1950 (Reel 997)
  - Radio--General vol. 2, 1948-1949 (Reel 1012)
  - Robinson-Patman Act briefs, 1945 (Reel 431)
  - Robinson-Patman Act vol. 1, 1939-1949 (Reel 998)
  - RTDG--Agreement and negotiation, 1950-1952 (Reel 1012)
  - Salary schedule, New York, 1956 (Reel 1009)
  - Screen Actors Guild, 1952-1953 (Reel 998)
  - Screen Actors Guild, 1952-1955 (Reel 1009)
  - Screen Publishers Guild, 1949-1950 (Reel 999)
  - Talent salary stabilization, 1942-1952 (Reel 1012)
    Includes Treasury Dept. rulings
  - Taxes, 1939-1942 (Reel 1009)
  - Taxes--Excess profits data, 1936-1946 (Reel 1009)
  - Taxes--Revenue Acts, 1943, 1948 (Reel 999)
  - Television, 1949-1954 (Reel 1012)
  - Television facilities, 1946-1950 (Reel 999)
  - Television facilities, 1951-1953 (Reel 1012)
    NBC vol. 2
  - Trade publications rates, 1950-1951 (Reel 1012)
  - Trademarks, 1940-1953 (Reel 999)
  - TVA Code, 1950-1954 (Reel 999)
  - U.S. Trade Mark Association vol.1, 1951-1955 (Reel 1012)
  - Union matters, 1954-1956 (Reel 1012)
  - Union matters, vol. 1, 1946-1951 (Reel 999)
  - Union matters, vol. 1-2, 1941-1949 (Reel 1009)
  - United Hospital Fund campaign, 1956 (Reel 1009)
  - Warrants of attachment (garnishees), closed, 1951-1956 (Reel 1012)
  - Warrants of attachment (garnishees), vol. 1-2, 1945-1951 (Reel 999)
- Accounts, 1916-1958 and undated; 2
  - A. Rhodes Company, 1916-1944 (Reel 414)
  - Air India, 1956 (Reel 1010)
  - Alexander Smith, 1953 (Reel 994)
  - Alexander Smith, 1955 (Reel 995)
  - Alexander Smith, 1956 (Reel 1010)
    Marked "missing" in paper guide
  - Aluminium Ltd., 1951-1953 (Reel 994)
  - Aluminium Ltd., 1954 (Reel 998)
  - Aluminium Ltd., 1955 (Reel 995)
  - Aluminium Ltd., 1956 (Reel 1010)
  - Aluminium Ltd., 1957 (Reel 1008)
  - American Associates, 1947 (Reel 740)
  - American Bankers Association, 1956 (Reel 1010)
  - American Medical Association, 1954-1955 (Reel 995)
  - American Medical Association, 1956 (Reel 1010)
  - American Red Cross, 1957 (Reel 1008)
  - American Trucking Association, 1953 (Reel 994)
  - Anthracite Institute, 1945 (Reel 431)
  - Anthracite Institute, 1945-1948 (Reel 873)
  - Anthracite Institute, 1946 (Reel 739)
  - Anthracite Institute, 1947 (Reel 740)
  - Anthracite Institute, 1949 (Reel 743)
  - Anthracite Institute, 1950 (Reel 745)
  - Arnold Schwinn, 1950 (Reel 745)
  - Associated Hospital Service of N.Y., 1953 (Reel 994)
    (Blue Cross and Blue Shield)
  - Associated Hospital Service of N.Y., 1954 (Reel 998)
  - Associated Hospital Service of N.Y., 1955 (Reel 995)
  - Associated Hospital Service of N.Y., 1956 (Reel 1010)
  - Associated Hospital Service of N.Y., 1957 (Reel 1008)
  - Atlantis Sales, 1943 (Reel 401)
  - Atlantis Sales, 1944-1945 (Reel 431)
  - Atlantis Sales, 1946 (Reel 739)
  - Atlantis Sales, 1947 (Reel 740)
  - Atlantis Sales, 1948 (Reel 741)
  - Atlantis Sales, 1950 (Reel 745)
  - Atlantis Sales, 1953 (Reel 994)
  - Atlantis Sales, 1954 (Reel 998)
  - Atlantis Sales, 1955 (Reel 995)
  - Atlantis Sales, 1956 (Reel 1010)
  - Atlantis Sales, 1957 (Reel 1008)
  - Ballantine, 1944-1945 (Reel 431)
  - Ballantine, 1946 (Reel 739)
  - Ballantine, 1947 (Reel 740)
  - Ballantine, 1948 (Reel 741)
  - Ballantine, 1949 (Reel 743)
  - Ballantine, 1949 (Reel 994)
  - Ballantine, 1950 (Reel 745)
  - Ballantine, 1950 (Reel 995)
    Transcribed spots
  - Ballantine, 1952-1955 (Reel 993)
  - Ballantine, 1953 (Reel 994)
  - Ballantine, 1953-1954 (Reel 996)
    Foreign Intrigue; letters, general correspondence, miscellaneous sponsors
  - Ballantine, 1953-1954 (Reel 997)
    Sports tie-ins; jingles; spot campaigns
  - Ballantine, 1954 (Reel 994)
  - Ballantine, 1955 (Reel 995)
  - Ballantine, undated (Reel 995)
    Claim file: "Deep Brewed Brew"; "Winter Wonderland"
  - Ballantine, undated (Reel 998)
  - Bank of America, 1944 (Reel 431)
  - Better Homes & Gardens, 1956 (Reel 1010)
  - Bio-Research, 1951 (Reel 873)
  - Blue Shield, 1955 (Reel 1012)
    Claim Files--Knoll Associates
  - Borg-Warner, 1947 (Reel 740)
  - Borg-Warner, 1950 (Reel 745)
  - Borg-Warner, 1953 (Reel 994)
  - Borg-Warner, 1954 (Reel 998)
  - Borg-Warner, 1955 (Reel 995)
  - Borg-Warner, 1956 (Reel 1010)
  - Borg-Warner, 1956 (Reel 1010)
  - Bowman Dairy, 1944-1945 (Reel 431)
  - Bowman Dairy, 1946 (Reel 739)
  - Bowman Dairy, 1947 (Reel 740)
  - Bowman Dairy, 1948 (Reel 741)
  - Bowman Dairy, 1950 (Reel 745)
  - Bowman Dairy, 1953 (Reel 994)
  - Bowman Dairy, 1954 (Reel 998)
  - Bowman Dairy, 1955 (Reel 995)
  - Bowman Dairy, 1956 (Reel 1010)
  - Boyle-Midway, 1954 (Reel 998)
  - Boyle-Midway, 1955 (Reel 995)
  - Boyle-Midway, 1956 (Reel 1010)
  - Boyle-Midway, 1957 (Reel 1008)
  - Brillo, 1947 (Reel 740)
  - Brillo, 1949 (Reel 743)
  - Brillo, 1953 (Reel 994)
  - Brillo, 1954 (Reel 998)
  - Brillo, 1955 (Reel 995)
  - Brillo, 1956 (Reel 1010)
  - Brillo, 1957 (Reel 1008)
  - Buitoni Foods, 1955 (Reel 995)
  - Buitoni Foods, 1956 (Reel 1010)
  - Buitoni Foods, 1957 (Reel 1010)
  - Burlington Industries (Pacific Craft), 1956 (Reel 1010)
  - Burlington Industries (Pacific Craft), 1957 (Reel 1008)
  - Burroughs, 1950 (Reel 745)
  - Burroughs, 1953 (Reel 994)
  - Burroughs, 1954 (Reel 998)
  - Burroughs, 1955 (Reel 995)
  - Burroughs, 1956 (Reel 1010)
  - Burroughs, 1957 (Reel 1008)
  - Buxton, 1924-1948 (Reel 873)
  - Buxton, 1944-1945 (Reel 431)
  - Buxton, 1946 (Reel 739)
  - Buxton, 1947 (Reel 740)
  - Buxton, 1948 (Reel 741)
  - Buxton, 1949 (Reel 743)
  - Buxton, 1950 (Reel 745)
  - California Truck Rental, 1949 (Reel 873)
  - Calvo Growers of California, 1946 (Reel 739)
  - Carter Products, 1947-1949 (Reel 743)
  - Carter Products--Australia, New Zealand, 1943 (Reel 315)
  - Carter Products--Superin, 1942 (Reel 315)
  - Carter's Ink, 1945 (Reel 431)
  - Caterpillar, 1948 (Reel 873)
  - Central Manufacturing District, 1955 (Reel 995)
  - Central Manufacturing District, 1956 (Reel 1010)
  - Champion Spark Plug, 1953 (Reel 994)
  - Champion Spark Plug, 1955 (Reel 995)
  - Champion Spark Plug, 1956 (Reel 1010)
  - Champion Spark Plug, 1957 (Reel 1008)
  - Chesebrough-Pond's, 1955 (Reel 1012)
  - Chesebrough-Pond's, 1956 (Reel 1010)
  - Chesebrough-Pond's, 1957 (Reel 1008)
  - Chun King, 1954 (Reel 998)
  - Chun King, 1955 (Reel 995)
  - Chun King, 1956 (Reel 1010)
  - Chun King, 1957 (Reel 1008)
  - Church & Dwight, 1948-1950 (Reel 745)
  - Church & Dwight, 1953 (Reel 994)
  - Church & Dwight, 1954 (Reel 998)
  - Church & Dwight, 1955 (Reel 995)
  - Church & Dwight, 1956 (Reel 1010)
  - Church & Dwight, 1957 (Reel 1008)
  - Ciba Pharmaceuticals, 1955 (Reel 995)
  - Ciba Pharmaceuticals, 1956 (Reel 1010)
  - Ciba Pharmaceuticals, 1957 (Reel 1008)
  - Coleman Mustard, undated (Reel 1013)
  - Columbia Distribution, undated (Reel 1013)
  - Columbia Mills, 1953 (Reel 994)
  - Columbia Mills, 1954 (Reel 998)
  - Columbia Mills, 1955 (Reel 995)
  - Columbia Mills, 1956 (Reel 1010)
  - Committee for Community Automobile Rates, 1950 (Reel 745)
  - Committee for Community Automobile Rates, 1950 (Reel 873)
  - Cuna, 1953 (Reel 994)
  - Cuna, 1954 (Reel 998)
  - Cuna, 1956 (Reel 1010)
  - D.P. Bushnell, 1950 (Reel 745)
  - Delson Candy, 1952 (Reel 873)
  - Devoe & Raynolds, 1949 (Reel 743)
  - Devoe & Raynolds, 1950 (Reel 745)
  - Devoe & Raynolds, 1953 (Reel 994)
  - Devoe & Raynolds, 1955 (Reel 995)
  - Devoe & Raynolds, 1955 (Reel 1012)
    Claim Files--Mr. and Mrs. Jack Kimmel
  - Devoe & Raynolds, 1956 (Reel 1010)
  - Devoe & Raynolds, 1957 (Reel 1008)
  - Douglas Aircraft, 1950-1952 (Reel 994)
    Security clearances
  - Douglas Aircraft, 1953 (Reel 994)
  - Douglas Aircraft, 1954 (Reel 998)
  - Douglas Aircraft, 1955 (Reel 995)
  - Douglas Aircraft, 1956 (Reel 1010)
  - Douglas Aircraft, 1957 (Reel 1008)
  - DuPont, 1956 (Reel 1010)
  - E.F. Hutton, 1956 (Reel 1010)
  - E.J. Brach & Sons, 1950 (Reel 745)
  - Eastside Brewing, 1956 (Reel 1010)
  - Economic Cooperation Administration, 1950 (Reel 873)
  - Elgin National Watch, 1945 (Reel 431)
  - Elgin National Watch, 1946 (Reel 739)
  - Elgin National Watch, 1946-1951 (Reel 745)
  - Elgin National Watch, 1947 (Reel 740)
  - Elgin National Watch, 1948 (Reel 741)
  - Elgin National Watch, 1949 (Reel 743)
  - Elgin National Watch, 1957 (Reel 1008)
  - Employers Mutual of Wausau, 1957 (Reel 1008)
  - Evans Bicycle, 1955 (Reel 995)
  - Evans Bicycle, 1956 (Reel 1010)
  - Evans Products, 1957 (Reel 1008)
  - Fanny Farmer Candy Shops, 1944 (Reel 431)
  - Fanny Farmer Candy Shops, 1946 (Reel 739)
  - Fanny Farmer Candy Shops, 1947 (Reel 740)
  - Fanny Farmer Candy Shops, 1949 (Reel 743)
  - Fanny Farmer Candy Shops, 1950 (Reel 745)
  - Farrell Lines, 1954 (Reel 998)
  - Farrell Lines, 1955 (Reel 995)
  - Farrell Lines, 1956 (Reel 1010)
  - Fieldcrest Mills, 1957 (Reel 1008)
  - Florida Citrus Commission, 1950 (Reel 745)
  - Florida Citrus Commission, 1953 (Reel 994)
  - Florida Citrus Commission, 1953-1954 (Reel 994)
  - Florida Citrus Commission, 1954-1955 (Reel 998)
  - Ford, 1944-1945 (Reel 738)
  - Ford, 1945-1947 (Reel 999)
  - Ford, 1946 (Reel 739)
  - Ford, 1946-1949 (Reel 743)
    Television Vol.1
  - Ford, 1947 (Reel 740)
  - Ford, 1948 (Reel 741)
    Anglia-Prefect dealers
  - Ford, 1949 (Reel 744)
    Through the Crystal Ball
  - Ford, 1950 (Reel 745)
  - Ford, 1951-1953 (Reel 994)
    Dr. Marshall; Marilyn Monroe
  - Ford, 1952 (Reel 1013)
    Ford v. Ferguson lawsuit
  - Ford, 1952-1953 (Reel 994)
  - Ford, 1952-1957 (Reel 1005)
    Ford Theatre vol. 1-12
  - Ford, 1952-1957 (Reel 1005)
    Ford Theatre vol. 1-4; Marion Preston files
  - Ford, 1953 (Reel 994)
    Television Vol. 4
  - Ford, 1954 (Reel 997)
  - Ford, 1954 (Reel 998)
    Screen Gems miscellaneous, vol. 1-2
  - Ford, 1954 (Reel 998)
    Ford/Reader's Digest series
  - Ford, 1954-1955 (Reel 998)
    Claim files--George Mustapha; Vulgar Curiosity
  - Ford, 1954-1956 (Reel 1012)
    Claim Files--Julie Chitwoof, Margaret Mumby, Edgar Parker, James Rodgers, Mrs. George Ross, Robert Sherman, Storyboard Inc., High Tor
  - Ford, 1955 (Reel 995)
  - Ford, 1955 (Reel 998)
    Closed circuit television
  - Ford, 1955 (Reel 1012)
  - Ford, 1956 (Reel 1010)
  - Ford, 1956-1957 (Reel 1010)
  - Ford, 1957 (Reel 1008)
  - Ford, 1958 (Reel 1013)
    Shaw v. Ford Motor Company
  - Ford Dealer, 1946 (Reel 739)
  - Ford Dealer, 1946-1953 (Reel 994)
  - Ford Dealer, 1947 (Reel 740)
  - Ford Dealer, 1947-1948 (Reel 741)
  - Ford Dealer, 1948 (Reel 741)
  - Ford Dealer, 1949 (Reel 743)
  - Ford Dealer, 1950 (Reel 745)
  - Ford Dealer, 1952-1957 (Reel 1008)
    Price advertising essentials
  - Ford Dealer, 1953 (Reel 994)
  - Ford Dealer, 1953 (Reel 995)
  - Ford Dealer, 1954 (Reel 997)
  - Ford Dealer, 1954-1955 (Reel 995)
  - Ford Dealer, 1954-1955 (Reel 996)
  - Ford Dealer, 1955-1956 (Reel 1009)
  - Ford Dealer, 1956 (Reel 1010)
  - Ford Dealer, 1957 (Reel 1008)
  - Fred Astaire Dance Studios, 1947 (Reel 740)
  - General Cigar, 1932-1951 (Reel 873)
    Letters of terms, contracts
  - General Cigar, 1944 (Reel 430)
  - General Cigar, 1946 (Reel 739)
  - General Cigar, 1947 (Reel 740)
  - General Cigar, 1948 (Reel 741)
  - General Cigar, 1949 (Reel 744)
  - General Cigar, 1950 (Reel 745)
  - Guinness, 1946 (Reel 739)
  - Guinness, 1947 (Reel 740)
  - H.C. Cole Milling, 1946 (Reel 739)
  - H.C. Cole Milling, 1947 (Reel 740)
  - H.H. Hinson, 1956 (Reel 1010)
  - H.H. Hixon, 1955 (Reel 995)
  - Harold F. Ritchie (Macprin), 1957 (Reel 1008)
  - Indiana Bell Telephone, 1953 (Reel 995)
  - Institute of Life Insurance, 1948 (Reel 741)
  - Institute of Life Insurance, 1950 (Reel 745)
  - Institute of Life Insurance, 1953 (Reel 995)
  - Institute of Life Insurance, 1955 (Reel 995)
  - Institute of Life Insurance, 1956 (Reel 1010)
  - Institute of Life Insurance, 1957 (Reel 1008)
  - International Mercantile (Panama Pacific Line), undated (Reel 1013)
  - Irving Trust, 1944 (Reel 430)
  - Irving Trust, 1946 (Reel 739)
  - J. Walter Thompson, 1956 (Reel 1012)
    Claim Files--Castle Offset Printing v. Warwick & Legler, Seagram
  - J. Walter Thompson, 1957 (Reel 1008)
  - J.B. Williams, 1941 (Reel 315)
  - J.B. Williams, 1943-1945 (Reel 401)
  - J.B. Williams, 1944 (Reel 430)
  - J.B. Williams, 1946 (Reel 740)
  - J.B. Williams, 1947 (Reel 741)
  - J.B. Williams, 1948 (Reel 742)
  - J.B. Williams, 1949 (Reel 745)
  - J.B. Williams, 1950 (Reel 746)
  - J.B. Williams, 1953 (Reel 995)
  - J.B. Williams, 1954 (Reel 997)
  - J.B. Williams, 1955 (Reel 996)
  - J.B. Williams, 1955 (Reel 998)
    Beau Kreml, Federal Trade Commission
  - J.B. Williams, 1955 (Reel 998)
  - J.B. Williams, 1956 (Reel 1011)
  - J.B. Williams, 1957 (Reel 1008)
  - Jerclaydon, 1952 (Reel 873)
  - John Irving Shoe Co., 1949 (Reel 744)
  - John Troll, 1946 (Reel 740)
  - John Troll, 1947 (Reel 741)
  - Johns-Manville, 1944 (Reel 430)
  - Johns-Manville, 1946 (Reel 739)
  - Johns-Manville, 1948 (Reel 741)
  - Johns-Manville, 1949 (Reel 744)
  - Johns-Manville, 1950 (Reel 746)
  - Johns-Manville, 1953 (Reel 995)
  - Johns-Manville, 1954 (Reel 997)
  - Johns-Manville, 1955 (Reel 995)
  - Johns-Manville, 1956 (Reel 1010)
  - Johns-Manville, 1957 (Reel 1008)
  - Johns-Manville, undated (Reel 994)
  - Johnson Motors, 1957 (Reel 1008)
  - Joint Shoe Committee, undated (Reel 1013)
  - Kellogg, 1941 (Reel 315)
  - Kellogg, 1944 (Reel 430)
  - Kodak, 1947 (Reel 740)
  - Kodak, 1948 (Reel 741)
  - Kodak, 1949 (Reel 743)
  - Kodak, 1950 (Reel 745)
  - Kodak, 1953 (Reel 994)
  - Kodak, 1954 (Reel 998)
  - Kodak, 1955-1956 (Reel 995)
  - Kodak, 1955-1957 (Reel 1010)
  - Kodak, 1956 (Reel 1010)
  - Kodak, 1956 (Reel 1012)
    Norby settlement, marked missing in paper guide
  - Kodak, 1957 (Reel 1008)
  - Kodak, undated (Reel 994)
    International film commercials
  - Kraft, 1944 (Reel 430)
  - Kraft, 1945 (Reel 430)
  - Kraft, 1946-1948 (Reel 743)
  - Kraft, 1947 (Reel 740)
  - Kraft, 1948 (Reel 741)
  - Kraft, 1948 (Reel 994)
  - Kraft, 1949 (Reel 744)
  - Kraft, 1950 (Reel 746)
  - Kraft, 1952 (Reel 995)
    Kraft Television Theatre
  - Kraft, 1953 (Reel 995)
  - Kraft, 1953-1957 (Reel 1008)
  - Kraft, 1954 (Reel 997)
  - Kraft, 1954-1955 (Reel 996)
  - Kraft, 1955 (Reel 998)
    Claim files--Man Who Made the Kaiser Laugh (marked missing); Papa Was a Sport; My Sob, The Doctor; Edgar Bergen Show
  - Kraft, 1955-1956 (Reel 1010)
  - Kraft, 1955-1956 (Reel 1012)
    Claim Files--Jeanne, Man Who Made the Kaiser Laugh, Two Times Two
  - Kraft, 1956 (Reel 1010)
  - Kraft, 1956 (Reel 1012)
    Television "A Night to Remember"
  - Kraft Music Hall--In the Bitter Root Valley, 1941 (Reel 375)
  - Langendorf Bakeries, 1947 (Reel 740)
  - Langendorf Bakeries, 1948 (Reel 741)
  - Lever Brothers, 1924-1945 (Reel 284)
  - Lever Brothers, 1932-1943 (Reel 315)
  - Lever Brothers, 1939 (Reel 375)
    Lever Hermanos Ltd (South America); see also reel 315
  - Lever Brothers, 1942 (Reel 375)
  - Lever Brothers, 1942 (Reel 375)
    Lux block contracts; see also reel 161
  - Lever Brothers, 1942 (Reel 401)
    Photostats, not distinct on reels 315, 375; see reel 315 for rest
  - Lever Brothers, 1943 (Reel 401)
    Copyright material
  - Lever Brothers, 1943 (Reel 430)
    Frank Sinatra contract; RKO and American Tobacco
  - Lever Brothers, 1943-1945 (Reel 430)
    Vimms; De Mille; AFTRA; Lux
  - Lever Brothers, 1943-1945 (Reel 738)
  - Lever Brothers, 1945 (Reel 739)
  - Lever Brothers, 1946 (Reel 739)
    Vol. 1: Lever, Vimms, War Bond contest
  - Lever Brothers, 1946 (Reel 739)
    Vol. 2: Canada
  - Lever Brothers, 1946-1953 (Reel 994)
    Pepsodent; Rayve; International; Anne Sheridan; Mary Martin
  - Lever Brothers, 1947 (Reel 740)
  - Lever Brothers, 1947 (Reel 741)
    Vol. 1 continued, Vol. 2; Canada
  - Lever Brothers, 1948 (Reel 741)
  - Lever Brothers, 1948 (Reel 742)
    Includes Rayve, foreign campaigns
  - Lever Brothers, 1949 (Reel 744)
    Includes Canada, international
  - Lever Brothers, 1950 (Reel 746)
    Canada
  - Lever Brothers, 1950s (Reel 993)
    Helen Greensward claim (Pepsodent)
  - Lever Brothers, 1951-1952 (Reel 995)
  - Lever Brothers, 1952-1953 (Reel 1010)
    Lux Video Theatre
  - Lever Brothers, 1953 (Reel 995)
  - Lever Brothers, 1953-1955 (Reel 998)
    Claim files--Place in the Sun; To Each His Won; Emerson College; Monte Fleischman; James Mason (marked missing)
  - Lever Brothers, 1954 (Reel 997)
  - Lever Brothers, 1955 (Reel 996)
  - Lever Brothers, 1955 (Reel 1012)
    Television vol. 1-3
  - Lever Brothers, 1955-1956 (Reel 1012)
    Claim Files--Pamela Wright, Thyra Samter Winslow
  - Lever Brothers, 1956 (Reel 1010)
  - Lever Brothers, 1956-1957 (Reel 1008)
  - Lewis-Howe, 1956 (Reel 1010)
  - Libby McNeil & Libby, 1943 (Reel 401)
  - Libby McNeil & Libby, 1944 (Reel 430)
  - Libby McNeil & Libby, 1945 (Reel 431)
  - Libby McNeil & Libby, 1946 (Reel 739)
  - Libby McNeil & Libby, 1947 (Reel 741)
  - Libby McNeil & Libby, 1948 (Reel 742)
  - Libby McNeil & Libby, 1949 (Reel 744)
  - Libby McNeil & Libby, 1950 (Reel 746)
  - Libby McNeil & Libby, 1953 (Reel 995)
  - Libby McNeil & Libby, 1954 (Reel 997)
  - Libby McNeil & Libby, 1955 (Reel 996)
  - Libby McNeil & Libby, 1956 (Reel 1010)
  - Libby McNeil & Libby, 1957 (Reel 1008)
  - Lincoln-Mercury Dealer, undated (Reel 1013)
  - Lorillard, 1942 (Reel 375)
  - Lorillard, 1942 (Reel 401)
  - Lorillard, 1943 (Reel 401)